Geziel Elyon Barbosa Costa

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/gezielelyon Email: geziel_barbosa_@hotmail.com
GitHub: https://github.com/gezielelyon Mobile: 5581999792393

Skills

• Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Golang, Python

• Frontend React, Next, HTML, CSS, Vite, Gatsby, React Native, Tailwind CSS, Material UI,

Technologies: Shadcn UI, Radix, Bootstrap, Styled Components, Sass

• Backend

Technologies:Node, Nest, Adonis, ApolloGraphQL, Express, Fastify, Rest API, GraphQL, Web Socket

Databases: SQL, NoSQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MySQL, SQLite, Firebase, Elasticsearch
 Devops: Docker, K8s (Kubernetes), Terraform, Git, Github, Github Actions, Datadog
 Tests: Unit, Integration, E2E, Contract, Jest, Vitest, Cypress, Testing Library

• Code Quality: Clean Code, Clean Architecture, Design Patterns, SOLID

Cloud: AWS (Amazon Web Services), Vercel, Render

Applications: Microservices, Monolithic, Serverless
 Queue and cache: Apache Kafka, RabbitMQ, Redis

Summary

Experienced software engineer with a background in planning, developing, scaling, architecting, securing, and maintaining large-scale web applications, microservices, and APIs in critical environments, serving millions of users daily, for the financial, banking, education and security sectors. I consider myself passionate about solving problems and helping people. I love technology and all the possibilities it offers. If there's a problem, there's a way to solve it with technology. My main focus is delivering and adding value to the company and team that I'm working on with all my professional experiences.

Experience

StoneRio de Janeiro, BrazilSoftware engineerJan 2024 - Present

- I created several security automations to protect the company's intellectual property like the codes on the Github and the client's data.
- I created new products for engineering teams including security services to facilitate the analyzing, granting and revoking access to company assets.
- I made code refactorings and performance improvements in several web applications using good practices such as Clean Code, Clean Architecture, Design Patterns and SOLID.
- Context: Stone is one of the biggest payments and finance companies in Brazil and Latin America. It offers
 payments and banking services to other big companies, so there are millions of users using its systems every
 day.

Pagar.meRio de Janeiro, BrazilSoftware engineerSep 2022 - Dec 2023

- I created a new reading layer architecture that increased the performance by 30% and brought more reliability in storage data.
- I broke a huge monolith into microservices separated by context, bringing more reliability and ease of maintenance.
- I made code refactorings and performance improvements in several legacy applications using good practices such as Clean Code, Clean Architecture, Design Patterns and SOLID.
- **Context:** Pagar.me is one of the biggest payments and finance companies in Brazil. I was responsible for the entire reading layer, for attacking technical debts and making performance improvements in several of the company's applications and services, and working horizontally with the company's other teams.

Mais Retorno São Paulo, Brazil

Fullstack software engineer

Jan 2022 - Aug 2022

- I built new complex tools for the finance market such as the assets and funds comparator, income simulator, fund tracker, fund and stock sheets, government bonds and direct treasury.
- I created a complete recurring subscription system for members have access to private finance tools and advantages.
- I made code refactoring and performance improvements in several applications and services using good practices such as Clean Code, Clean Architecture, Design Patterns and SOLID.
- **Context:** Mais Retorno is a financial market and education company. It offers many tools for investors. I was responsible for planning, developing and improving new tools and products for the financial market, for fixing bugs and for helping my coworkers.

Mais Retorno

Frontend developer

São Paulo, Brazil Jun 2021 - Dec 2021

- I built new features, fixed bugs and made several SEO improvements in the company's main web application.
- I made several SEO and performance improvements in the company's main web application.
- **Context:** I was responsible for creating new landing pages, developing new features, helping team members, planning the sprints, fixing bugs, building new tools and for making SEO improvements in all platforms.

Education

UNIFG

Software Engineering, Programming Languages, Software Requirements, Cloud Platform etc... Bachelor of Computer Science, Information Technology Jun 2021 - Jun 2024

Rocketseat

Development with Javascript, Typescript, NodeJs, React, Next, HTML, CSS, Golang, and Devops.

Professionalizing school, Information Technology Jan 2020 - Present